<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
	<channel>
		<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title>
		<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com</link>
		<description>Breaking science news and articles on global warming, extrasolar planets, stem cells, bird flu, autism, nanotechnology, dinosaurs, evolution -- the latest discoveries in astronomy, anthropology, biology, chemistry, climate and environment, computers, engineering, health and medicine, math, physics, psychology, technology, and more -- from the world's leading universities and research organizations.</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 13:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 13:30:01 EDT</lastBuildDate>
		<ttl>60</ttl>
		<image>
			<title>Latest Science News -- ScienceDaily</title>
			<url>https://www.sciencedaily.com/images/scidaily-logo-rss.png</url>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com</link>
			<description>For more science news, visit ScienceDaily.</description>
		</image>
		<atom:link xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/rss/" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<item>
			<title>The most precise accounting yet of dark energy and dark matter</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019111358.htm</link>
			<description>Analyzing more than two decades&#039; worth of supernova explosions convincingly bolsters modern cosmological theories and reinvigorates efforts to answer fundamental questions. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 11:13:58 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019111358.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meet the first Neanderthal family</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019111328.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have managed to sequence multiple individuals from a remote Neanderthal community in Siberia. Among these thirteen individuals, the researchers identified multiple related individuals -- among these a father and his teenage daughter. The researchers were also able to use the thirteen genomes to provide a glimpse into the social organization of a Neanderthal community. They appear to have been a small group of close relatives, consisting of ten to twenty members, and communities were primarily connected through female migration. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 11:13:28 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019111328.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Physicists confirm hitch in proton structure</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019111327.htm</link>
			<description>A new precision measurement of the proton&#039;s electric polarizability has confirmed an unexplained bump in the data. The proton&#039;s electric polarizability shows how susceptible the proton is to deformation, or stretching, in an electric field. Like size or charge, the electric polarizability is a fundamental property of proton structure. The data bump was widely thought to be a fluke when seen in earlier measurements, so this new, more precise measurement confirms the presence of the anomaly and signals that an unknown facet of the strong force may be at work. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 11:13:27 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019111327.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Beauty products with fluorinated ingredients may also contain PFAS, study reports</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090742.htm</link>
			<description>Smooth, foamy, water-proof. These characteristics are extremely desirable in beauty products, but manufacturers sometimes use ingredients that contain fluorine -- including potentially harmful per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) -- to achieve them. Now, researchers show that some cosmetics and personal care products labeled as having fluorinated components also contain PFAS, whether or not these &#039;forever chemicals&#039; were listed as ingredients. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:07:42 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090742.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Our brains use quantum computation</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090732.htm</link>
			<description>A team of scientists believe our brains could use quantum computation, after adapting an idea developed to prove the existence of quantum gravity to explore the human brain and its workings. The brain functions measured were also correlated to short-term memory performance and conscious awareness, suggesting quantum processes are also part of cognitive and conscious brain functions. Quantum brain processes could explain why we can still outperform supercomputers when it comes to unforeseen circumstances, decision making, or learning something new, while the discovery may also shed light on consciousness, the workings of which remain scientifically difficult to understand and explain. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:07:32 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090732.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Warmer climate causing acidification of the Arctic Ocean</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090730.htm</link>
			<description>Climate change is causing the Arctic Ocean&#039;s sea ice to melt away. When the polar ocean loses its cover of sea ice, carbon dioxide uptake increases disrupting the food web in the water according to a new study. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:07:30 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090730.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No heart damage despite hypertension</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090720.htm</link>
			<description>An overactive enzyme that causes an inherited form of high blood pressure also appears to protect against hypertension-induced cardiac damage. A team of researchers explains how this could fundamentally change the way hearts can be protected from damage. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:07:20 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090720.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Drones show potential to improve salmon nest counts</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090718.htm</link>
			<description>A study showed that drone photography of the Wenatchee River during spawning season can be effective in estimating the number of rocky hollows salmon create to lay their eggs, also called &#039;redds.&#039; <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:07:18 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090718.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Large emissions from ship scrubbers</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090710.htm</link>
			<description>The Baltic Sea is considered one of the world&#039;s most polluted seas. Now, new research reveals a relatively unknown environmental culprit. The study shows that the discharge water from ships&#039; exhaust gas treatment systems, so-called scrubbers, is responsible for up to nine percent of certain emissions of carcinogenic and environmentally harmful substances in the Baltic Sea, which is considerably more than was previously known. Furthermore, the number of ships equipped with scrubbers have tripled since the study was carried out. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:07:10 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221019090710.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Model calculates energetics of piercing fangs, claws and other biological weapons</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220546.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have created a model that can calculate the energetics involved when one organism stabs another with its fangs, thorns, spines or other puncturing parts. Because the model can be applied to a variety of organisms, it will help scientists study and compare many types of biological puncturing tools, researchers said. It also will help engineers develop new systems to efficiently pierce materials or resist being pierced. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 22:05:46 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220546.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ancient viral remnants in the human genome are active in normal tissues</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220543.htm</link>
			<description>Remnants of ancient viruses in the human genome are active in healthy tissues as well as diseased ones, limiting their utility as disease biomarkers, according to a new study. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 22:05:43 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220543.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Five hours&#039; sleep a night linked to higher risk of multiple diseases</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220538.htm</link>
			<description>Getting less than five hours of sleep in mid-to-late life could be linked to an increased risk of developing at least two chronic diseases, finds a new study. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 22:05:38 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220538.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New motorcycle lighting design could save lives</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220535.htm</link>
			<description>Motorcycle drivers are 27 times more likely to die in an accident than those in regular passenger vehicles. Night driving is especially dangerous, accounting for nearly half of all fatal crashes. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 22:05:35 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220535.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Warming oceans likely to shrink the viable habitat of many marine animals -- but not all</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220428.htm</link>
			<description>A new article adds a new chapter to the story of how some animals may respond to the warming oceans. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 22:04:28 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018220428.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Attack on 2 fronts leads ocean bacteria to require carbon boost</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131222.htm</link>
			<description>The types of ocean bacteria known to absorb carbon dioxide from the air require more energy -- in the form of carbon -- and other resources when they&#039;re simultaneously infected by viruses and face attack from nearby predators, new research has found. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:12:22 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131222.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Nanoporous intermetallic compounds that boost hydrogen production</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131200.htm</link>
			<description>Hydrogen, a clean fuel, is incredibly dense in energy -- three times more than diesel or gasoline. Its ability to power a sustainable future has been hindered by a lack of high performing catalysts. Now, a collaborative research group has developed nanoporous molybdenum-based intermetallic compounds that could address this conundrum. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:12:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131200.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Reliably estimating proportion of vaccinated populations in wildlife</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131158.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers develop a ground-breaking model to estimate bait vaccination effectiveness in wild animals based on the proportion of immunized animals in a population and the number of vaccine applications. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:58 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131158.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Color-changing fibers for smart clothes</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131153.htm</link>
			<description>When we think about clothing, we usually think of it as something we wear to cover our body, convey our style and protect us from the environment. What if the cloth changes its visual appearance when you stretch your hand?... such mechanoresponsive material has enormous potential in a large range of transformative applications in the beauty and health industry. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:53 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131153.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Light-driven molecular swing</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131150.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have used ultrashort laser pulses to make the atoms of molecules vibrate and have gained a precise understanding of the dynamics of energy transfer that take place in the process. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:50 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131150.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Skin-attachable auditory sensor that functions even in noisy environments</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131149.htm</link>
			<description>A research team has developed a skin-attachable auditory sensor, which recognizes human voices in noisy environments and when users wear facemasks. The new sensor will be useful in microphones that facilitate communication in disaster situations and for healthcare devices that diagnose respiratory diseases. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:49 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131149.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Plants use their roots to measure manganese concentration available in the soil</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131146.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers demonstrate for the first time, using the model plant thale cress (Arabidopsis thaliana), how plants perceive manganese deficiency and which processes subsequently take place in the plant at the molecular level. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:46 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131146.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Mona Lisa effect: How eyespots deter predators that approach from different directions</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131145.htm</link>
			<description>The eyespots of many prey animals deter predators from attacking, like those of the peacock butterfly. In a new study, researchers show that the configuration of eyespots have an impact on the prey&#039;s survival. The deterrent potential of eyespots is larger when they appear to look directly at a predatory chick. The most effective deterrent are concentric circles that subjectively appear to maintain eye contact regardless of the perspective from which they are approached. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:45 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131145.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Treatment for back pain: 84 percent increase in success rate</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131143.htm</link>
			<description>If a therapy for chronic back pain is tailored specifically to a patient&#039;s individual requirements, the chances of success are far greater than with standard forms of treatment. Accompanied by a psychotherapeutic procedure in the shape of cognitive behavioral therapy, the pain can be alleviated even more effectively. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:43 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131143.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Artificial intelligence answers the call for quail information</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131139.htm</link>
			<description>When states want to gauge quail populations, the process can be grueling, time-consuming and expensive. It means spending hours in the field listening for calls. Or leaving a recording device in the field to catch what sounds are made -- only to spend hours later listening to that audio. Then, repeating this process until there&#039;s enough information to start making population estimates. But a new model aims to streamline this process. By using artificial intelligence to analyze terabytes of recordings for quail calls, the process gives wildlife managers the ability to gather the data they need in a matter of minutes. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:39 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131139.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Individualized fingerprints from sleep brainwaves provide a powerful new tool for understanding disease</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131133.htm</link>
			<description>A team led by researchers has developed a powerful computational tool for understanding brain health and disease, providing an enhanced way of characterizing the activity of the brain during sleep. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:33 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131133.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Differences in male and female ostriches could explain how they form groups</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131131.htm</link>
			<description>Males and females are affected in different ways by cooperation and competition in social groups -- something that could determine which group sizes work best. According to a new study, this depends to a large extent quite simply on females and males having different interests. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:31 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131131.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Scientists compile Cassini&#039;s unique observations of Saturn&#039;s rings</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131129.htm</link>
			<description>Scientists have compiled 41 solar occultation observations of Saturn&#039;s rings from the Cassini mission. The compilation will inform future investigations of the particle size distribution and composition of Saturn&#039;s rings, key elements to understanding their formation and evolution. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:29 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131129.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Study suggests support across Europe for COVID-19 vaccine equity</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131121.htm</link>
			<description>A new study suggests that Europeans are willing to prioritize COVID-19 vaccines for individuals at risk in the Global South over those in their own countries. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:21 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131121.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Researchers 3D bioprint breast cancer tumors, treat them in groundbreaking study</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131115.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have successfully 3D bioprinted breast cancer tumors and treated them in a breakthrough study to better understand the disease that is one of the leading causes of mortality worldwide. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:11:15 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131115.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Wastewater testing expected to work for most infectious diseases</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131014.htm</link>
			<description>Wastewater surveillance of infectious diseases is expected work for just about every infectious disease that affects humans, including monkeypox and polio. But more research is needed to apply the science for public health benefit, according to a research team led by epidemiologists. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:10:14 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018131014.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Introducing FathomNet: New open-source image database unlocks the power of AI for ocean exploration</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018130553.htm</link>
			<description>FathomNet can help train and test computer machine learning tools to accelerate analysis of ocean images and video. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 13:05:53 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018130553.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Native predatory fish help control invasive species in Hawaiian fishpond</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091858.htm</link>
			<description>Jacks and barracuda in He?eia fishpond were found to feed on Australian mullet, an invasive species introduced to Oahu waters in the 1950s. This recently published finding suggests that these native predatory fish may provide a form of biocontrol on populations of the invasive mullet species in a traditional Hawaiian fishpond. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:18:58 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091858.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cancer-seeking molecular delivery system could boost immunotherapy drug</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091852.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have demonstrated a promising new approach to delivering immunotherapy agents to fight cancer. The approach involves tethering an immunotherapy agent called a STING agonist to an acid-seeking molecule called pHLIP® (pH-low insertion peptide). The pHLIP molecules target the high acidity of cancerous tumors, delivering their immunotherapy cargo directly to cells in the tumor microenvironment. Once delivered, the STING agonists engage the body&#039;s innate immune response to fight the tumor. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:18:52 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091852.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Asian elephants prefer habitats on the boundaries of protected areas</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091849.htm</link>
			<description>New research, offering a comprehensive analysis of Asian elephant movement and habitat preference, finds that elephants prefer habitats on the periphery of protected areas, rather than the areas themselves. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:18:49 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091849.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New machine-learning technique for classifying key immune cells has implications for a suite of diseases</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091847.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have developed a new, machine learning-based technique to accurately classify the state of macrophages, which are key immune cells. Classifying macrophages is important because they can modify their behavior and act as pro- or anti-inflammatory agents in the immune response. As a result, the work has a suite of implications for research and has the potential to one day make major societal impact. For example, this new approach could be of use to drug designers looking to create therapies targeting diseases and auto-immune conditions such as diabetes, cancer and rheumatoid arthritis -- all of which are impacted by cellular metabolism and macrophage function. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:18:47 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091847.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Intermetallic palladium-zinc alloy: a corrosion-resistant, highly active, low-cost electrocatalyst</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091844.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have created intermetallic alloy nanoparticles of palladium and zinc with an alternating arrangement of zinc and palladium atoms. The intermetallic alloy is more corrosion-resistant than substitutional alloys while retaining the electrocatalytic properties of both metals, which could be useful for developing new non-precious metal electrocatalysts. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 09:18:44 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221018091844.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Photo-taking helps students remember slide content</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017174905.htm</link>
			<description>A new study finds that taking pictures of PowerPoint slides during an online presentation helped students remember the slide content better than for slides they did not photograph. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 17:49:05 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017174905.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hitting the snooze button? You&#039;re far from alone, study shows</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017174902.htm</link>
			<description>A study found that 57 percent of the participants were habitual snoozers. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 17:49:02 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017174902.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Flooding significantly impacts food security</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161121.htm</link>
			<description>New research finds that flooding can affect food security for over 5.6 million people across several African nations. The work comes at a time when floods have also devastated Pakistan, India, and large parts of the European Union and the United States. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 16:11:21 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161121.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Isotope data strengthens suspicions of ivory stockpile theft</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161119.htm</link>
			<description>A new study uses carbon isotope science to show that marked tusks in a seized ivory shipment were more than 30 years old and likely had found their way from a guarded government stockpile into the hands of illegal ivory traders. The results suggest that governments that maintain ivory stockpiles may want to take a closer look at their inventory. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 16:11:19 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161119.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Targeting enzyme could alleviate muscle wasting for cancer patients</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161116.htm</link>
			<description>Targeting a specific enzyme in the muscle could help cancer patients preserve muscle mass and potentially prolong their survival, according to new research. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 16:11:16 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161116.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Neanderthals appear to have been carnivores</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161113.htm</link>
			<description>For the first time, zinc isotope ratios in tooth enamel have been analysed with the aim of identifying the diet of a Neanderthal. The Neanderthal to whom the tooth belonged was probably a carnivore. Other chemical tracers indicate that this individual did not consume the blood of their prey, but ate the bone marrow without consuming the bones. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 16:11:13 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161113.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Metabolism, not genes, may offer more insight into risk of some diseases</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161110.htm</link>
			<description>In an analysis of the metabolic profiles of healthy American babies, researchers found surprising differences among ethnic groups which may help make screening for inherited metabolic disorders, cystic fibrosis, or hypothyroidism much more accurate than traditional genetic disease screens. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 16:11:10 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161110.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New analysis of obsidian blades reveals dynamic Neolithic social networks</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161107.htm</link>
			<description>An analysis of obsidian artifacts excavated during the 1960s at two prominent archaeological sites in southwestern Iran suggests that the networks Neolithic people formed in the region as they developed agriculture are larger and more complex than previously believed. The study has applied state-of-the-art analytical tools to a collection of 2,100 obsidian artifacts. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 16:11:07 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017161107.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Algae-based food goes global: scaling up marine aquaculture to produce nutritious, sustainable food</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142531.htm</link>
			<description>Terrestrial agriculture provides the backbone of the world&#039;s food production system. A new article makes the case for increased investment in algae aquaculture systems as a means of meeting nutritional needs while reducing the ecological footprint of food production. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:25:31 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142531.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Advanced genomic approaches hold promise for marine conservation</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142525.htm</link>
			<description>Genetic and genomic technologies have tremendous potential for protecting marine life, but are currently being underutilized, according to a new article. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:25:25 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142525.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Future emissions from &#039;country of permafrost&#039; significant, must be factored into global climate targets</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142518.htm</link>
			<description>By the end of this century, permafrost in the rapidly warming Arctic will likely emit as much carbon dioxide and methane into the atmosphere as a large industrial nation, and potentially more than the U.S. has emitted since the start of the industrial revolution. A new study forecasts cumulative emissions from this &#039;country of permafrost&#039; through 2100 under low, medium, and high warming scenarios. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:25:18 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142518.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New dataset reveals biological &#039;treasure trove&#039; of Arctic Ocean</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142516.htm</link>
			<description>A major new project will help benchmark biodiversity change in the Arctic Ocean and guide conservation efforts by identifying unique species and assessing their extinction risk. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:25:16 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142516.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>High exposure to glyphosate in pregnancy could cause lower birth weights in babies</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142505.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers are learning more about the effects of herbicide exposure during pregnancy. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:25:05 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142505.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Eating fire ants could prepare lizards for future fire ant attack</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142457.htm</link>
			<description>Eating fire ants might prepare a lizard&#039;s immune system to be stung by the ants, according to a new study. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:57 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142457.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gene signature points to prognosis in kidney cancer</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142455.htm</link>
			<description>Among patients with kidney cancer, the activity of four specific genes in the cancer cells seems to be able to predict the risk of the tumor spreading and the patient&#039;s chances of survival. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:55 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142455.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>DNA gives colloidal crystals shape-shifting and memory abilities</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142451.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have uncovered a previously unknown property of colloidal crystals, highly ordered three-dimensional arrays of nanoparticles. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:51 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142451.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Air pollution from factories and vehicles linked to worse outcomes for patients with lung disease</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142449.htm</link>
			<description>People with a disease characterized by lung scarring that has no obvious cause are more likely to die if they live in areas with higher levels of air pollution composed of chemicals associated with industrial sources and vehicular traffic, according to new research. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:49 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142449.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A new AI model can accurately predict human response to novel drug compounds</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142448.htm</link>
			<description>A research team has created an artificial intelligence model that could significantly improve the accuracy and reduce the time and cost of the drug development process. The new model, called CODE-AE, can screen novel drug compounds to accurately predict efficacy in humans. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:48 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142448.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Deep learning tool identifies bacteria in micrographs</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142446.htm</link>
			<description>Omnipose, a deep learning software, is helping to solve the challenge of identifying varied miniscule bacteria in microscopy images. It can also identify several other types of tiny objects in micrographs. It was not easily fooled by extreme changes in a cell&#039;s shape due to antibiotic treatment or antagonism by chemicals produced during interbacterial aggression. In fact, it could even detect intoxication in E. coli. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:46 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142446.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Brain discovery holds key to boosting body&#039;s ability to fight Alzheimer&#039;s, MS</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142440.htm</link>
			<description>Researchers have discovered a molecule in the brain responsible for orchestrating the immune system&#039;s responses to Alzheimer&#039;s disease and multiple sclerosis (MS), potentially allowing doctors to supercharge the body&#039;s ability to fight those and other devastating neurological diseases. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:40 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142440.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>European colonial legacy is still visible in today&#039;s alien floras</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142438.htm</link>
			<description>Alien floras in regions that were once occupied by the same European power are, on average, more similar to each other compared to outside regions and this similarity increases with the length of time a region was occupied. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:38 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142438.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Study takes major step in pursuit of HIV cure</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142435.htm</link>
			<description>While the standard treatment for HIV can hold the disease in check, a new study shows how experimental medicines can boost the body&#039;s own ability to suppress the virus. An important step towards a cure, say researchers behind the study. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:35 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142435.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pregnancy could curb desire to smoke before it is suspected or recognized</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142433.htm</link>
			<description>Pregnant smokers reduced their smoking by an average of one cigarette per day before becoming aware they were pregnant, reports a new study of more than 400 pregnant people. Then, in the month after learning of their pregnancy, participants reduced smoking by another four cigarettes per day. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:33 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142433.htm</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>new sensor system for internet of things devices integrates processing and computing</title>
			<link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142431.htm</link>
			<description>Engineers have introduced a holistic system that integrates sensing, storage and processing at the sensor&#039;s edge to enable efficient and secure signal processing. Brain-inspired hardware minimizes power consumption for numerous applications requiring interpretation of visual images and ultrasound, chemical detection and bio-sensing, time-of-flight data for topological mapping and kinetics. <!-- more --></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 14:24:31 EDT</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2022/10/221017142431.htm</guid>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<!-- Page successfully written to cache. -->
<!-- Cached Wed, 19 Oct 2022 17:30:01 GMT -->
